何体くらい あるんだろうな？　これ。 約５０００だとよ。
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
それでも予定の５分の１くらいしか 集まってないらしい。 じゃあ　王様 相当おかんむりだろ。
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
いや　ずっと部屋で 遊んでるみたいだぜ。
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
メシも食わないで 軍儀に夢中になってるって。 じゃあ この食料　どうする気だよ。
The word "unknown" holds magic.
俺達で奪って食っちまうか？
And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
冗談にすら　なってねえ。
They are known...
初めて分かる強さって　あるよ 本当に。
...as Hunters!
テレパシー
Gon has learned the technique
テレパシー 宮殿のほうへ向かっています。 テレパシー 人形兵では　歯が立ちませんね かなりの手だれです。
which will enable him to
capture his target.
テレパシー
Ow!
テレパシー 殴打での応戦のみですね。
My hands are all bloody...
テレパシー よし　何か能力を使ったら すぐに知らせろ。
I've been swinging my fishing
rod for two straight days.
ヘッ…　ついでに ２人の能力もチェックしとくか
catching birds as they swoop
after their prey.
クソ！　見失った！
If I utilize this technique properly, I'll be able to steal Hisoka's tag.
テレパシー レオル様　どうやら　黒メガネは
All that's left is to find Hisoka!
テレパシー 自在に場所を 瞬間移動できるようです。
Ow...
ノヴの能力名は 「ハイドアンドシーク」
But how am I supposed to find Hisoka?
瞬間移動能力である 壁や地面に手をかざすと
I guess I'll just have to walk around,
and trust my instincts.
そこに　念空間へ通じる穴を 開けることができ その穴から　人や物を 転送させることが　できるのだ
What? Why are they gathering around me?
念空間である
These butterflies...
それぞれの部屋は 完全に独立していて 入り口は　部屋に入ったと同時に 閉じるため
They're attracted to the scent of blood.
部屋の大きさによって 上限が違う
Hisoka, have you taken your target's tag?
出口は　入って来た穴と つながっている
No, not yet.
つまり　ある部屋への出入りは
You don't even know who
your target is, do you?
原則として 同じ場所の穴からしかできない
No. Want me to tell you?
ただし　ノヴの持つ マスターキーならば
No, it doesn't matter.
部屋の出口を　どの場所の穴とも つなげることが　できる
I'll just find three others to hunt.
異常なし 平和な戦闘のままだな
I remember that, back at the tower,
Hisoka was injured.
モラウの「ディープパープル」は 基本的に専守防衛 味方以外のものと遭遇すれば 一定の距離をとり
If this works, the butterflies
might lead me to him.
投げたり　殴ったりすること
Ah...
念人形であることを 悟らせないためである
It's the guy who was grazed
by the arrow.
ここは戦闘地域からは だいぶ離れているのに…
Better luck next year!
やっぱ　たぬき寝入りだ！ そのては　食わないよ！
There he is!
お前が追っかけて来るまで ここで　騒いでやる！
Stay calm...
バカ　そうさせたかったら 初めから 追っかけざるを得ないような
Stay calm!
勝手にしろよ。 とにかく　あと５時間は 起きねえからな。
I just need to wait.
あ…。 足での勝負に　かなりの こだわりがあるようだな
For Hisoka to make his move.
他人に構ってもらいたい性格と 合わせて考えてみても 他の勝負に変えて来る 可能性は低い
Man, where is everyone hiding?
う！　絶対に寝させないよだ！
I haven't seen anyone for
the past two days.
オイ！　こっち見ろ！ ほらほら　触れるぞ！　起きろ！
Who's there?
うっわ こんな近くまで来ちゃったよ。
Oh, hold on!
根比べ　奴が もし途中で諦めて
It's just me... Tonpa!
俺のそばから離れたら…
Don't tell me that your target is... Hey, wait a second! Just calm down.
俺の勝ちだ
You aren't my target.
９－９－１　「帥」。
Don't tell me that I'm your target!
１－５－１　「帥」。
Unfortunately, you're not.
７－９－１　「兵」。
#246.
２－３－１　「兵」。
Ponzu, huh? Huh?
８－１－１　「忍」。
You know who this is? You didn't already know?
２－３－１　「砲」。
Uh, er, well...
９－１－１　「砦」。
I wouldn't put it that way. I just didn't have a chance
to find out...
２－７－２　「筒」。
Heh. Want me to fill you in?
「帥」を孤立。
What?
「離隠」とでも　名付けておくか。
Your target's appearance, weapons, special abilities, and weaknesses.
７－１－２　「砦」。 １－６－２　「大将」。
However, I have one condition.
９－１－３　「弓」。
Huh? I think I ate some bad fruit.
３－２－２　「少将」。
Bad fruit...
済みだ。
To be honest, I can barely stand...
奴の初期配置は予想通り
You want to become a doctor, right?
こちらの帥に　やや寄せながらも 鶴羽の陣は崩さない
Do you have any medicine on you? I got it...
へば　お願いいたすます。
Don't soil yourself.
１手目で　右翼に「弓」を据え 「槍」３本の速攻を 決める腹だろうが
I have all kinds of anti-diarrheal
and stomach medicine. Oh...
右に寄せてできた左翼の空白に
Thank you so much! First, tell me what you know.
余の持ち駒が死角をつくる
F-Fine...
乱してやる　其方の呼吸
Ponzu is a female applicant.
１－９－３　「弓新」。 来たな！
As far as I know, five of the remaining
twenty-four applicants
９－７－１　「忍新」。
use some sort of chemical weapon.
２－９－１　「騎馬」。
Ponzu is one of those.
「槍」３本と左辺の攻防で
So she's the one.
余のほうが駒２枚　失う
This girl happens to specialize in all kinds of drugs.
その代償でできた 其方の左翼の死角
But her strategy is simple...
玉砕覚悟で　ここから攻め寄ると 思っているだろう
Hide and wait. Hide and wait?
違うな！ ここだ!!
She sets a trap and waits for
her target to show up. I see...
５－５－１　「中将」。
You shouldn't have to worry
about anything else.
よどみなく一定のリズムで 打っていた彼女の手が
If you find her, watch your footing, and note which
direction the wind is blowing.
マジで行くぞ！ よどみなく一定のリズムで 打っていた彼女の手が 初めて止まった マジで行くぞ！ 初めて止まった
Sh-She's fully aware that
someone else
この配置 盤中央からの攻防は無限！
is targeting her.
正着は　ない
Th-That's pretty much it.
こちらの対応次第で いくらでも長引く１局
G-Give me the medicine... Okay.
さぁ　聞かせてみよ
To be safe, back up a bit.
其方の　あえぎ！
H-Hurry... I-I can't hold it in!
９－２－１　「中将新」。
Your tag is mine.
詰みだ。
I have my own. And I might as well confess
貴様　これが 「死路」であることを
that you actually are my target.
知っていたな？
Wh-What about the card you
just showed me?
はい。
That's my target.
なぜ　手を止めて 考える必要があった？
This is Tonpa's.
ノータイムで打てる 一手であろうが!?
We swapped cards.
王の盤外からの一手 返答を誤れば
And you fell for our little trick...
死にますよ
There you have it.
総帥様の お考えになられた「離隠」は
Damn you! I'll make you pay!
正すい名前を 「狐狐狸固」と言いますて
Uh-oh... Tonpa! We'll meet at the usual place!
ワダすが考えますた。
Gotcha!
「槍」３本に対すて 中心に「中将」を置くのも
Hold up! I'm gonna kill you! Hey, now...
「中中将」という ワダすの新手です。
I'm not the one with your tag!
これが　当時は話題になりますて。
Shut up! Good grief...
「狐狐狸固」から「中中将」は 互いの読みの力を試される
You still haven't learned
your lesson, rookie? What was that?
優秀な戦法として大流行すますた。
It's your own fault for letting us trick you!
何か　バカなワダすからでも
Besides, working in teams during the
Hunter Exam is common sense!
こんな利口なコが 生まれんのかって 結構　うれしかったんだけども
I agree with the latter,
but I cannot accept the former. Huh?
国内の名人戦で　相手が 「狐狐狸固」を仕掛けて来た時
Kurapika... Leorio, want to team up?
この手に気付いてすまったんです。 勝負には勝ちましたが それ以降　このコは
Hunter Vocabulary
公式戦や書物からは 姿を消すますた。
Target
一度　死んだ我が子が 生き返ったような…。
Hey!
そんな気がすたんです。
Return my tag!
だから　もう一度　このコの
If you want it back, catch me.
フン　くだらぬ。 興がそがれた　しばし休め。
Okay! I retrieved my tag.
あっ…。
And we have the tags for
#16 and #118, as well.
次に始めたら
So, Kurapika, Tonpa was your target?
休憩は　一切なしだ　覚悟しておけ。
You saved me back there. You needn't thank me.
はっ　はい！
I didn't want Tonpa to notice me, so I stayed hidden
王様が　あれほど長い間 黙って人の話を聞いたのは
while you were jumped from behind. What? Well, that was because I figured there'd be no point in teaming up
初めてですね…　まぁ
with you if you couldn't
withstand that attack.
それだけのこと
I suppose that you barely qualified.
４時間経ったか ハハハ…！
You really are full of yourself... Well, I can't deny that it's easier
to work as a team.
フフ… 結局　飽きて読書だもんな
Let's stick together for the
remaining four days.
分かりやす過ぎて 張り合いがねえぜ
Yes.
ハハハ…！
You got your target's tag.
あっ。
So with your own, that adds
up to six points.
おっ　始める？ もう５時間経ったのか？
Assuming he doesn't take it back.
あれ？　まだ半分くらいじゃん。 ハハハ！　やっぱ少し焦って来た？
The #118 tag is only worth
one point for either of us.
ニャハハ…　んっ？
But it might still come in handy.
気付いたか？
Next, we need to find your target, #246, Ponzu.
始めんじゃねえ　終わってんだ。
Stay alert, in case we're being followed.
自分の足首　見てみな。
You shouldn't be talking. Yeah, yeah.
煙のロープ!?
You're absolutely right.
うわ！
I know you've been following me
since the exam began.
煙だと思って　ナメちゃいけねえ。
Show yourself.
切断不可能の綱だと思いな。
Let's play.
ヂートゥの能力は まさに発展途上
Well, come on out.
ギリギリに 追い込まれたことで
I know you're there.
この困難な現状を 何とか打破すべく…
He noticed me?
あっ？ 新たな能力を生み出した！
If you won't come out, I'll come to you.
ボーガンとクロウ。
I guess that's it... In that case, it's all or nothing.
お前のおかげで　すっげぇ能力 手に入っちゃった！ おいおい… これ　何か分かってる？
When did he arrive?
いいんだよ。
I challenge you to a duel.
お前なぁ 自分の足より遅いもんを 能力にして　どうすんだよ。
You'll die.
そっちの爪も試してみねえか？ 俺のほうから 近づく手間が省けるんだがな。
This is my chance!
ヘッ　ヘヘヘ…。 うっせぇ！
My chance is about to come... In the moment Hisoka goes
to finish off his prey!
まさか
Why?
煙？　まさか!?
Why isn't Hisoka fighting back?
まず　自分のすぐ前に 煙でコピーを制作。
Hisoka, explain yourself...
自分の体を 草に　模した煙で覆い
Why won't you attack me?
コピーとは反対側から接近。 寝ている時も戦闘中だぜ。
If I continue to avoid your attacks, you'll die eventually.
無事　帰還か さて　まだやるかい？
I can tell from the swarm of
Hemotropic Butterflies that your wounds are grave.
いや　もういいや。 うん　それが賢明だな。
Someone else has already dealt
you a fatal blow, yes?
じゃ　もう教えてくれても いいんじゃねえか？
Though I do understand your
desire to die in battle.
俺が　もしも時間内に お前を捕まえられなかったら
If you...
どうなってたんだよ？ 聞いても意味ないぜ。 一度でも　俺が捕まっちゃえば もう　あの能力は二度と使えない。
If you understand so well, why do you still refuse to fight me?!
そういう条件で つくった能力だから。
I have no interest in the dead.
そうかい　悪いことしたかねぇ。
What?
ハッ！　どうってことないね。
I'm not yet...
また　シャウ様に 新しい能力をもらうさ！
You're already dead.
次は絶対に負けないからな！ 覚悟しとけよ!!
It's in your eyes.
恐らく直属護衛軍の シャウって奴が
Bye-bye.
強いのか？ それが分かれば苦労しない。
Sorry about that.
今は　互いに 間合いをはかってる感じだな。
I carelessly let him escape.
膠着状態か。
Liar.
時間を稼ぎたい 俺達にとったら願ったりだな。
He probably begged you to grant him
恐らく　俺が あいつを仕留めたからだ。
one final wish, yes?
あのトンボが　監視カメラの 役割を果たしていたらしい。
Well, I felt sorry for the guy. Given that he was dead either way.
テレパシー フラッタ！　応答しろ！
You should cease pitying enemies
who serve no purpose.
いくら待っても来ねえな。
You've done it before, haven't you?
作戦変更だな。 フラッタ抜きじゃ 敵の位置を把握できないんだろ？
You've walked away from opponents
before finishing them.
クソ。
I have standards.
肝心な時に使えねえ野郎だ
I'm not interested in people
who have no purpose.
中止か？　いや　ダメだ！
I only spare those whose deaths
would go to waste.
ピトーの評価を下げるわけには 絶対いかねえ！
What about his tag?
じゃ　俺達　戻るぜ。
Oh, I already took it.
あっ　待ってくれ！
I have six points now,
so I don't need this one.
分かった　俺が何とかする。
You can have it.
それが　お前の能力か？
It belonged to some guy
who tried to snipe me.
ああ　探索能力がある 他には黙ってろよ。 お前らだから見せたんだ。
He ticked me off, so I killed him.
レオルの「レンタルポッド」は 対象者に恩を売り
Well, then...
能力名を知る
This is always so fascinating to watch.
２つ目は　その後 相手に恩を売り 「これは貸しだからな」とか 「タダじゃないぜ」などと確認し
It's pretty hard on me...
それに対して 相手が同意した場合に限り 能力の発動条件が整う
I feel much better.
いつでも確認できるようになる
Well, I'll just sleep here
until the final day.
ただし　相手が死亡した場合
Good luck.
フラッタの「サテライトンボ」が 黒メガネの位置を確認したら 作戦スタートだ。
It's completely dark now.
一人で大丈夫かよ？ 任せとけよ ヤバい役目は　回さねえさ。
Night provides the perfect chance for
someone to attack their target. I know that.
…っていうか　お前らに 能力　見られたくねえんだよ
Well, I need two more points. I suppose I should go hunt someone...
どんな手　使っても ミッションは成功させるぜ ＯＫ…　と
I'll get him this time!
心身湯立つほど 受け入れがたい屈辱！
Found you...
だが…　苛立ちながらも
Hisoka targets Kurapika and Leorio.
それを楽しんでいる自分が 一方にある
Gon targets Hisoka's ID tag.
その源泉が分からぬ…
Four days remain before the
exam's Fourth Phase ends.